

Senior Software Developer

Personal Info:

- GitHub
- LinkedIn
- Iran-Tehran
- (98)919-5062977
- saba.marzoughi18@gmail.com

About Me:

I'm a software developer with 2 years of professional full-time experience in frontend development, alongside 3 years of part-time learning and practice in this field. During my professional journey, I've gained valuable experience working on diverse projects, improving my skills in various programming languages and development tools. In my spare time, I've been dedicated to selfimprovement and working on personal projects. I enjoy problem-solving, collaborating with teams. I'm excited for my next challenge where I can develop and work on attractive mobile/web applications and be a part of a strong software engineering team.

Skills:

- Programming Languages
 - JavaScript, TypeScript
- Front-end technologies
 - HTML5, CSS3, SASS
 - React
- Design
 - OOP, FP
- Cross Platform Apps:
 - React-Native (Android, iOS)
 - Electron (Windows, MacOS)
- State Managements
 - Redux, Context
- ALM
 - GitOps
 - Postman
 - Jira, Trello, Figma
 - Strapi (Content Manager)
- DB solutions
 - Realm
- API paradigms
 - REST, GraphQL

Education:

(Sep 2017-Des 2021)

 Bachelor of Computer Engineering (Software)

Work Experiences:

Senior Front-end developer at UniPlato:

Australia (Remote),

Aug 2022 - May 2023,

Visit Project

About **Coffee**: This is a meeting platform for scheduling and managing meetings with individuals or group of people.

- Upgraded the "Coffee" platform by refactoring the old code structures of 2 old modules and bringing them back to the project.
- Enhanced platform stability by conducting code reviews for new team members.
- Strengthened the codebase by developing over 15 pixel-perfect, responsive and well-structured **React** components, making them accessible to all team members across various modules as part of our design system.
- Delivered over 10 new features, complete with demos, to the platform through collaborative communication with team members and the adept utilization of REST APIs and web sockets.
- Directed the Mac desktop app functionalities, prioritising features and managing development to align with user needs and business objectives.
- Front-end developer at Comfortel:

Russia (Remote),

Dec 2021 - May 2022,

Visit Project

About **Comfortel:** This was an Internet service provider company in which our team was consist of over 15 members.

- Elevated team communication by implementing customizations across the Mattermost platform, ensuring a seamless experience on desktop (Windows and Mac) using **Electron** as well as mobile apps (Android)
- Enhanced the usability of the "Techpal" platform by launching its desktop application on three different operating systems (Windows, mac, and Linux) with Electron, while also developing its Android application using React-Native.
- Front-end developer (Freelancing & Open-Source):

Tehran

Nov 2020 - Des 2021

Visit Project

About **MyPlayer**: This is an open-source React Native project, serving as an audio/video provider platform. It utilizes Strapi as its content management system and its accessible on both iOS and Android operating systems.

- Transitioned from class-base structures to functional ones, to harness the power of hooks. This transformation let to a remarkable 30% performance enhancement particularly noticeable on older Android devices.
- Refactored old code structure that resulted in removing useless and extra packages from the project and reduced the bundle size.
- Front-end developer at <u>Bytino</u>:

Tehran,

Nov 2019 - Nov 2020

About **Bytino**: It is a startup team comprising frontend, backend, designer members with primary mission being the creation of outstanding webpages

- Improved team's portfolio resulting in the acquisition of 2 new projects by creating one-page websites that showcased our capability.
- Created webpage templates that have the potential to expedite project implementation.